我要他24小时受到监控
I want him under 24-hour surveillance.
行刑时我必须在场
I have to be there when they kill this man.
你至少可以回顾一下此案
The least you could do is review his case.
特伦斯
Terrence.
我不能明白的是 随着事情搞得越来越糟
The thing I can't quite figure is with the crap storm this thing's become
他们怎么还没杀了你
why they haven't killed you.
好好享用吧
Have at it.
看在你以前的份上
Now, out of respect for what you once were,
今天我放过你
I'm going to let you walk away.
为什么不把刀子给我呢?
Why don't you just hand me that shank you're holding?
我不明白你要这个干什么
I'm not even sure why you need it.
谢谢
Thank you.
钥匙就在你的邮件箱里
Your keys, they were right over there by your in-box.
有个维修工在外面等着
Well, you got a maintenance guy waiting outside here,
说是你要他来换锁 要我叫他走吗?
says you want him to change the locks. Want me to call him off?
不 叫他进来
No, send him in.
给你最后一个机会 特维纳
It's your last chance, Tweener.
斯科菲尔德他们那帮家伙... 他们在越狱
Scofield and his whole PI crew, they're escaping.
你知道我不可能让你走得了 头儿
You know I can't let you leave here, boss.
警犬
Dogs.
我曾不知多少次试图逃避上头的逮捕 但都被抓
The numerous times I've been apprehended while trying to elude the authorities,
就是因为这该死的警犬
it's always because of the damn dogs.
你逃得了一切
Turns out you can run from just about everything in your life
但逃不了你身上的臭味儿
except your own particular stink.
是么 有些人可能太臭了
Yeah, well, some of us stink more than others.
你大概闻起来有巧克力棒棒糖味
Kinte, you can smell like a bouquet of bonbons,
除非你把这味道弄掉
but unless you get rid of your smell
否则这等于给警察通信
you might as well send a note to the police
给他们指明方向 或许还免了他们的"打的"费
with directions and some cab fare.
他说得没错
You know, Theodore's right, man.
我们都得去除体味
We gotta scrub down our cells.
床铺怎么办?
What about our bunks?
枕头 床单等都得去除这个味道 要不干脆换了
Pillows, sheets, everything. Either get rid of your smell or change it.
我们还剩多少时间?
Well, how much time we got?
-约翰?  -3天
-John?  -Three days.
要把我们都弄到警卫室去工作 3天是最起码的
That's the soonest I could get us into the guards' room for PI.
那时候你可以弄到警服吗?
You think you'll have the extra suits by then?
可能吧 明天就应该可以弄到
Probably. They should be here tomorrow.
好 我们可以走了
Good, so we're good to go.
看来只需要想办法把医务室钥匙搞到就行了
how to get through that door in the infirmary.
还有把林肯弄出那牢房
How to get Linc out of that box.
你可以在三天内完成?
And you can do that in three days?
三天已经足够
Three days should be plenty of time.
我们得行动了
We got to get out of here.
现在就行动
Now.
我不知道怎么被他发现的 但他确实发现了
I don't know how he found it. He just did.
-那个洞就这么敞开在那里?  -我尽量把它盖得没有痕迹
-So the hole's just sitting there?  -I covered it the best I could
但他们迟早会发现贝利克失踪了
but it's just a matter of time before someone discovers
Bellick's missing.
什么意思 贝利克失踪了?
What do you mean Bellick's missing?
好 好 好
Okay, okay, okay.
狐狸河地方比较大 或许一时半会儿他们发现不了
Fox River is a big place. Maybe they won't notice for a while.
贝利克不下命令 这边什么事情都动不了
Nothing happens around here without Bellick's say so.
很快有人就会发现他失踪的
Somebody is gonna notice that he's missing.
一旦发现他失踪 他们一定会封锁这地方直到找到他为止
And when they do, they're gonna close this place down until they find him.
-我们怎么办?  -天一黑下来...
-What are we gonna do?  -As soon as it gets dark, we go.
-我们就走  -今晚?
-Tonight?  -Pretty,
我们还没准备好今晚逃跑
we ain't ready to escape tonight.
逃跑已经开始了 贝利克发现洞的那一刻就开始了
Escape already started. It started the minute Bellick found that hole.
发现他失踪的时候 一切就结束了
And it's gonna end the minute they figure out that he's missing.
那你留下来
Then stay!
我哪天早上肯定会看到报纸上说...
I'll be sure to read the papers in the morning.
他们发现有哪些人在那房间工作过
See how many years you got when they realized
谁挖了地洞 得判多少年
which crew was working in that room and dug that hole.
那我们具体该怎么做 伙计?
So what's the play, man?
今晚能把飞机准备好吗?
Do you think you can have the plane ready by tonight?
当然
Sure.
-你要去厨房值班 对吗?  -是的
-You had kitchen duty, right?  -Yeah.
你用什么东西洗地板的?
What'd you use to scrub down the floors?
我想应该是过氧化氢之类的东西
I don't know. I think it was some peroxide, or something like that.
那应该可行 你尽量拿 越多越好
That'll work. Get as much as you can.
我想办法去搞钥匙
I'll work on getting us that key to the infirmary.
其余的人想办法去除体味吧
The rest of you find whatever you can to get rid of the scent in your cells.
如果我们进不了警卫室 这些有什么用
None of this matters if we can't get in the guards' room.
我们晚饭后就走
We're gonna leave after dinner,
那段时间门是开着的
during tier time when the gates are open.
7:00 一个接一个 从我的房间出去
7:00, one by one, through my cell.
我们本应该从警卫室走的
Whoa, whoa. No, we were supposed to go through the guards' room.
在他们发现我们之前
That was going to give us a head start,
我们已经有足够的逃跑时间
hours before they even found out we were missing.
但如果从你的房间逃跑 时间就不多了
We leave through your cell, we ain't got no lead time.
-7:00 就算到8:00 那将是...  -60分钟
-7:00. Count's at 8:00, that's only...  -Sixty minutes.
60分钟内得翻过墙 并逃得越远越好
Sixty minutes to get over that wall and as far away from here as possible.
他们会马上追上来的
They'll be right on our asses.
停止聊天 回牢房去 户外活动时间到!
Quit your talking and start your walking. Ladies, yard time is over!
他们已经在追了
They already are.
一个接一个走
Come on, let's go. Hurry it up. Single file.
还有一件事我们没有谈起 你兄弟
You know, there's one thing we didn't talk about out there.Your brother.
我意思是 他受到了24小时监控
I mean, he's under 24-hour surveillance.
我是说 即使你今晚不能把他搞出来
I'm just saying, if you can't get to him by tonight,
我们也得走 这你很清楚的 是吗?
we still have to go, you know that, right?
-头儿  -你想要什么?
-Hey, boss.  -What do you want?
我兄弟在普通监区 他还不知道我发生了意外
My brother's in Gen Pop. He's got no clue I was in an accident.
所以?
So?
有什么法子我可以给他稍个信吗?
Well, is there any way I can get a message to him?
有 写在你的遗嘱里面
Yeah. Put it in your will.
你确定所有的点都有联系?
And you're sure all those dots connect?
好 谢谢
Okay. Thank you.
是谁?
Who was that?
律师事物所的一个朋友 处理公司的很多业务
A friend of mine at the title company, handled a lot of my firm's business.
对于布莱克福特的电话号码 她找了个地址给我
She dug up an address for that phone number in Blackfoot.
在哪?
Where is it?
有趣的不是那个地址 而是怎么个有趣法
It's not the where that's interesting, it's the how.
原来蒙大纳的那个地方
It turns out our little place in Montana
被一家海外的公司以2百万的价格买去了
was purchased for $2 million by an offshore holding corporation.
那些钱买那样的地 价格应该是合理的 不是吗?
Well, that's pretty standard for a transaction that size, though, right?
是的 可这家公司是由一家信用社提供资金的
Sure. Only this holding corporation was bankrolled by a trust.
而那家信用社 由特伦斯·斯蒂德曼的房产出资
A trust financed by the estate of Terrence Steadman.
看来我们得去布莱克福特看看了
Looks like you and I are going to Blackfoot, Montana.
-今天见到贝利克了吗?  -没有 怎么了?
-Have you seen Bellick today?  -No. Why?
麦柯刚在问 我想他还没来
Mack was asking. I guess he ain't showed up yet.
可能迟到了
He's probably just late.
贝利克? 我8年没看到他迟到过一回
Bellick? I haven't beat that guy to work in eight years.
斯科菲尔德 没什么好看的 快走
Scofield, this ain't Gibsons. Move.
他们已经开始怀疑了 伙计
They're already starting to ask questions, man.
我们不可能在7小时内离开这里 又保证不被他们发现那事
We're not gonna make it out of here in seven hours without them finding the answers.
那过氧化氢怎么样了?
How we coming with that peroxide?
在院子干活之前我要用到它
I'm gonna need it before we meet up for yard duty.
可能要之后才能搞到
Probably not till later.
能告诉我是干什么用的吗?
You wanna tell me what you need it for?
这些布鲁塞尔豆苗 你吃吗?
Makkos, you going to be eating them there Brussels sprouts?
不
No.
-你介意我...  -拿去吧. 他们闻起来像大便
-You mind if I...  -Take them. They smell like crap.
是吗?
Do they, now?
什么事?
What's up?
-如果你...  -今晚
-Yo, if you got...  -Tonight.
-什么?  -计划改变了
-What?  -Change of plans.
为什么 发生什么事了吗?
Why, did something happen?
去找苏克雷吧
Just find Sucre.
他会告诉你该做些什么准备
He'll tell you what you need to do to be ready.
-那...?  -今晚
-But what about the...  -Tonight.
发生什么事了?
What the hell's going on?
总统改主意了
The President changed his mind.
有保证说他一定会否决这个能源议案
We were given assurances he would veto the energy bill.
"保证"会告诉你一个人会怎么做
Assurances can tell you everything that a man is going to do
但有效期至第二天早上他醒来改变主意的时候
until he wakes up in the morning and changes his mind.
-那就改回来  -你没听明白
-Then change it back.  -I don't think you understand.
-总统...  -你喜欢我们的支持吗?
-The President...  -Have you enjoyed our support?
是的
Yes.
好 我们当然不会让你觉得这是理所当然的
Good. We certainly wouldn't want you to take it for granted.
-你在威胁我?  -怎么了?你觉得受到威胁了?
-Are you threatening me?  -Why? Do you feel threatened?
卡罗琳 这些我们都经历过
Caroline, we've all been through this before,
政治道德的潮起潮落
the ebbs and flows of political conscience,
但到了最后 我们总能得到我们想要的
but we've found at the end of the day we get what we want.
这只是个"谁帮我们"的问题
It's simply a matter of who helps us get it.
如果你不能说服那糟老头(总统)完成他的第二个任期
If you can't convince a doddering old fool finishing up his second term
从国家的经济利益考虑 问题在于...
what the best thing is for this country's economy,
也许你不是我们要找的那个人
perhaps you're not the kind of helper we're looking for.
莎拉... 我在想...
Sara. I was thinking about something...
够了 迈克尔
Enough, Michael.
所有的谎言 巧合 故事 都已经够了
Enough with the lies and the coincidences and the stories, all of it.
-事实不是你想像的那样  -我知道你干了什么
-It's not what you think.  -I know what you did.
问题是 你有没有勇气去承认它?
The question is, are you man enough to admit it?
那钥匙
The keys.
祝贺你
Congratulations.
这是你第一次跟我说实话吗?
Is that the first time you've been honest with me?
-这不是...  -第二次?
-It's not...  -The second?
你到底想干什么 迈克尔?
What are you after, Michael?
为了药物? 还是注射器?
Is it drugs? Is it needles?
-都不是  -那是为了什么?
-Neither.  -Then what?
请你明白 我不是本意要...
Please understand that I never meant...
我从没想过要把你卷进来的
I never wanted to involve you in this.
那你做得确实是有点差的
Well, you've done a pretty poor job of that.
我来这是来告诉你点事儿
I came here to tell you something.
我要把我哥哥弄出去
I'm getting my brother out of here.
今晚
Tonight.
我需要你的帮助
And I need your help.
迈克尔 老实跟你说 为了你自己 不要再说了
Michael, honestly, for your own good, don't say anything more.
你知道他是无辜的
You know he's innocent.
他如果按你说的做 他就不无辜了
Do what you're talking about and he won't be.
但他至少还活着
But he'll still be alive.
你明白我有责任向上头汇报一切
You understand that I'm required to report everything you're telling me.
-是的  -那你为什么还?
-Yes.  -Then why would you?
因为你是唯一一个能帮我的人
Because you're the only one that can help.
因为我知道 你想要成为解决问题的一部分
And because I know you want to be part of the solution.
协助和煽动可算不上解决问题的一部分
Yeah, aiding and abetting is not part of the solution.
知道真相却置之不理 也算不上解决问题的一部分
Neither is doing nothing knowing what you know about his case.
你竟敢把这些强加于我
How dare you put this on me.
我做了我所能做的 我把资料给我父亲看了...
I did what I could. I gave my father the information...
没有冒犯之意 但那些陷害林肯的家伙
No offense to your father, but the people who are framing Lincoln,
可以说是有相当高的安全警戒线
let's just say they have a higher security clearance.
照你说这成阴谋了?
So now it's a conspiracy?
我不是来这里跟你争的
I didn't come here to have a debate.
你是在请我去干不法勾当的
You're asking me to break the law.
我要你犯个小错误
I'm asking you to make a mistake.
不伤害任何人 不偷任何东西 就...
Not hurt anyone, not steal anything.
别锁门就行
Just forget to lock up.
你今晚下班的时候 别把门锁上
Leave the door unlocked when you leave tonight.
就这样 求你了
That's it. Please.
这就是越狱的地方? 这个房间?
This is where you're breaking out of? This room?
门周围的玻璃上装有报警器
There are alarm contacts on the glass surrounding the door.
否则我就不会要你...
Otherwise, I wouldn't need you to...
我一直都是你计划的一部分
I was part of your plan.
你全是在演戏?
Was it all an act?
开始的时候 是的
At first, yes.
我得来这儿
I needed to be here.
但后来我想要和你在一起
But then I wanted to be here with you.
对
Right.
知道你决不会相信这一切是一件很另人痛苦的事
And it's killing me to know that you'll never believe that.
不管你对我怎么想 我都是为了林肯
Whatever you may think of me, this is about Lincoln.
别因为我的错而让他受罪
Don't make him pay for my mistakes.
耶?
Yeah?
嘿 是我 看来要提前了
Hi, it's me. There's been an acceleration.
提前到什么时候?
How fast are we talking about?
-很快 就今晚  -狗娘养的
-Fast. Tonight.  -Son of a bitch.
我想你应该没什么问题吧?
I think what you're trying to say is, "No problem"?
是的 当然 我会搞定的
Yeah, of course. It'll be taken care of.
好.车子呢?
Good. The van?
在福驰街等着 200码...
Waiting up Fitz Street, 200 yards...
-老厂后面?  -老厂后面 明白了
-Behind the old mill?  -Behind the old mill, I got it.
有个问题 约翰 你不想来架大点的飞机吗?
One question, John. Don't you want a bigger plane?
这飞机只有三个位置 我记得你说过有7 8个人
You only got three seats. I thought you said there were seven or eight guys.
并不是每个人都能上飞机
Well, not everybody gonna have a ticket.
能告诉我是哪几个吗?
You gonna tell me who is?
那还活着的三个
The three of us still breathing.
两张票 接近布莱克福特的任何一个机场都行
Whatever airport's closer to Blackfoot.
是否靠窗等问题都不重要 给我们订下一班机的票子
Aisle, window, it doesn't matter, just get us on the next flight.
好 我等着
Yeah, I'll hold.
嘿?
Hello?
计划改变了
Change of plans.
今晚你就得把女孩带到机场跑道去
We're going to need you to have a girl at the airstrip tonight.
-今晚?  -我说得不够清楚吗?
-Tonight?  -Was I not enunciating?
不 只是 恩...
No, it's just that...
事情可能会变糟糕
Look, things could get messy.
穿上工作服吧
So wear a smock.
彼得森和监狱长的秘书?
Is that his nympho secretary?
你少来 伙计 好像你不会上似的
Come on, man, like you wouldn't hit that.
我不知道 维加斯 凌晨2点 或许吧 但...
I don't know, Vegas, 2:00 a.m., maybe, but
要不是她屁股那么大
if she didn't have such a big booty.
女人的屁股是男人最大的弱点 我知道我会上的
Man, the booty is the man's biggest weakness. I know I would've hit it.
可以去成医务室了?
You find a way to the infirmary yet?
我还在想办法
I'm working on it.
-嘿 你今天看到贝利克了?  -没看到
-Yo, you seen Bellick today?  -Not yet.
我要跟他谈一谈 你知道他去哪了吗?
I need to talk to him. Do you know if he went somewheres?
我看起来像他妈?
Do I look like his mother?
这家伙我今天还没看到过
The guy hasn't shown up yet.
你确定他今天没来?
You sure he ain't showed yet?
因为我想我今天早上看到他了
'Cause I thought I saw him here this morning, man.
特维纳 来这里帮我一把
Tweener! Need a hand over here.
好 我来了
Yeah, I'm on it.
-好了吧?  -好
-All right?  -Fine.
只是 恩... 有点痛 就这样
It's just sore, that's all.
等你活到我的岁数 你就知道了
You live to my age, you'll know all about it.
你知道你的母鸡屋里有几只狐狸 是吗?
You know you got a couple of foxes in your hen house, right?
你在说什么?
Who are we talking about?
那两个天生的死对头
The bastard and the born again.
他们俩都想离开这儿 那种时候不会闹事的
They both want out of here. They'll behave until then.
你这么想?
Think so?
我昨天从帝博格拿到这个
I just picked this off of T-Bag yesterday.
如果我晚到10秒种
If I would've been there 10 seconds later,
他们就得在太平间伺候那个浑身是血的阿布鲁奇了
they'd have been serving Abruzzi with red sauce over at the morgue.
我知道你想尽量减少麻烦 这没问题
I know you want to be shot caller and everything, and that's cool,
但你得解决这件事
but you got to handle things, man.
听明白我说的话了吗?
Are you picking up what I'm putting down?
是的
Yeah.
事情就这样了 这次千万不能出任何差错了
Look, this is it, man. Ain't no do-overs this time.
不能出现意外情况
Can't be no complications.
今晚出不去 我们就再也别想出去了
We break out tonight, or we ain't never getting out.
这是郡里拿来的书面材料
We got that paperwork in from the county.
莎拉?
Sara?
好. 抱歉
Yeah. Sorry.
郡里拿来的书面材料
The paperwork from the county.
好 知道了
Right. I got it.
帮我个忙 能帮我看一下这个吗?
Do me a favor, could you take care of that for me?
我得出去一趟
I got to get out of here.
-行  -谢谢
-Sure.  -Thanks.
-等等 你去哪?  -外面去
-Where are you going?  -Out.
干完活后衣服不要脱
Put your blues on over your PI gear.
-什么?  -照做就行了
-What?  -Just do it.
能讲讲原因吗?
You want to tell us why?
如果我们没时间拿到制服
If we don't have time to get the suits we need,
我们就不得不用这个代替
we're gonna have to make them.
你这是干什么 伙计? 有其它人在
Yo, what the hell are you doing, man? We got company.
没事儿 他和我们一起走
It's okay. He's coming with us.
你上次还说 "人太多了"?
Hey, whatever happened to, "We got too many people"?
计划改变了 时间也就改变了
When the plan changed, so did the timing.
我们要确保大家都出得去
I'll make sure we all get through.
从健康的角度考虑
Well, for health reasons,
这样的消息应该早点说
information like that should be disseminated a little more pronto.
嫩鸡
Uh-uh, Fish.
多个人就意味着 多一个环节会发生意外
One more person means there's one more thing that can go wrong.
-他不准来  -这已经没有商量余地了
-He is not coming.  -It's not up for discussion.
-怎么没有  -我欠他的
-The hell it ain't.  -I owe him.
我可什么也不欠你
I don't owe you a damn thing.
如果因为多了个人而使得我们被抓的话
Well, you're gonna if we get nailed 'cause you didn't wanna cut down on the damn guest list.
别担忧 没事的
Don't worry, it'll be fine.
等等
Hold up, cons.
那里面的地板上我看到有几滴血
I saw some drops of blood on the floor of the PI locker room.
谁告诉我这是怎么回事儿?
Now who's going to tell me what's going on?
应该是我 头儿
That'd be me, boss.
我 我卸载东西的时候割破了手
I did it while I was loading some equipment back into the shed.
记住去包扎一下
You make sure and get that patched up.
我会的
Will do.
好
Okay.
走吧
Move it!
你没事吧?
Are you okay?
足以撑到外面 我保证
Okay enough to make it out of here tonight, I swear.
雪丽 是 是我
Hey, Shelly, this is... It's me.
听着 我知道一旦我发生什么事... 应该打电话给你...
Listen, I know I'm supposed to call you as my sponsor, in case I have a...
好
Right.
我觉得我们应该开瓶香槟庆祝一下
I think we should break a bottle of champagne across its bow.
如果你打算今晚把这个带回家庆祝
If you're intending to get this thing home for your anniversary tonight,
我不建议你这么做
I wouldn't recommend it.
不是的
No.
听着 你要知道我...
Listen, I want you to know that I...
能遇到你真的很幸运
Well, I feel very fortunate to have met you.
是啊 很少会有建筑师来狐狸河
Yeah. I'm guessing not many structural engineers make their way into Fox River.
不 不 我那么说不是因为你的职业
No, no, I don't mean because of your vocation.
而是因为你是个很不错的年轻小伙
I mean because you're a decent young man,
而很少会有那样的人来到狐狸河
and there are not many of those who make their way into Fox River.
我这么说吧 其实还是有一些的
Well, for what it's worth, there are a few down there.
这倒挺不错
Well, that's good to hear.
听着 我知道这其实没必要说出来 但...
Listen, I know this goes without saying, but
如果你需要什么...
if there's anything you need...
这么说吧 我欠你一个人情
Well, let's just say that I owe you one.
事实上... 我确实有件事想要你帮忙
Actually, there is one thing you can do for me.
所以说这整件事其实并不是围绕我的
So this whole thing, this whole time, it was never about me.
而是和爸爸有关
It was about Dad.
我不能相信...
I can't believe it.
迈克尔? 迈克尔!
Michael. Michael!
什么?
What?
你没什么想告诉我的?
You got something you want to tell me?
我刚告诉你所有关于爸爸的一切其实是个谎言 而你眼睛都没眨一下
Just told you everything we knew about Dad was a lie,and you barely blinked.
我们得走了 今晚
We have to go. Tonight.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
贝利克发现那个洞了 要么现在就走 要么永远走不了了
Bellick found the hole, so either we go now or it's over.
迈克尔...
Michael.
听着 我知道时间很紧 但我做得到
Look, I know it's gonna be tight, but I can do this.
迈克尔 别说了
Michael, stop it.
这锁链 它们是 恩...
The chains on your locks, they're...
迈克尔! 迈克尔!
Michael! Michael!
-我能做到!  -听我说!
-I can do this!  -Listen to me!
-走吧 你得走了  -别那么说
-Go. You gotta go.  -Don't say that.
你看看我!
Look at me!
你做不到的 时间不允许了
You can't do this. There's not enough time.
如果你呆在这儿 他们一定会抓住你 你就死定了
If you stay here, they'll nail you and you'll rot in here.
我不是在请求 我是在告诉你
I'm not asking you, man, I'm telling you.
不要管我了
Leave me behind.
走吧
Go.
你他妈的在干什么?
What the hell you think you doing?
没什么 伙计
Nothing, man.
你想在我们亲爱的食物里面做手脚吗?
You trying to run something for those Wonder Breads you been running around with?
不 不是这样
No, it ain't even like that.
那你告诉我 小子
Tell me something, boy.
你在耍诡计还是玩阴谋?
Is you stepping or is you fetching?
我想我已经说得够明白了 你这蠢蛋不准再踏入我们的领地
I thought I made myself clear when I said your punk ass was no longer in business.
这不是你们的领地 好吧? 这是我私人的事情
This ain't business, all right? This is personal.
你在拿什么东西? 洗涤液?
What you got there anyway, some kind of cleaner?
你想洗什么...
What you trying to clean up,
富兰克林中士?
Sergeant Franklin?
前方记者南茜会作详细报导 南茜?
Nancy Lu has the details. Nancy.
副总统雷诺兹 竞选阵营中传出流言
And rumors coming out of Vice President Reynolds' camp
竞选伙伴的最初名单出了问题
detail a preliminary short list of running mates
她能够众望所归地得到任命吗?
should she, as expected, win her party's nomination.
也许最令人惊讶的是伊利诺斯州州长 弗兰克·唐克雷蒂卷入了此事
Perhaps the biggest surprise is the inclusion of llinois governor Frank Tancredi.
考虑到这可以归因于他在对待犯罪上一贯强硬的立场
His consideration is attributed to his reputation for being tough on crime.
尤其是近来在对待林肯·布伦斯这个案子上毫不手软
And some point to his recent refusal to grant clemency to Lincoln Burrows,
林肯·布伦斯是杀害副总统弟弟的凶手
the murderer of the Vice President's brother,
因此得到了白宫的一致赞赏和认同
which was welcomed with deep appreciation from within the Oval Office.
你他妈在干什么 约翰?
What the hell are you doing, John?
上帝的工作
Lord's work.
上帝要你把马粪撒在你的床垫上?
The Lord wants you to spread horse crap all over your mattress?
我们没权力质疑他的意愿
It's not in our place to question his will.
明白了吗?
Are we clear?
安静点
Hey, hey, hey! Let's cut the noise.
打开88号!
Open on 88!
-怎么了?  -艾拂卡托的东西
-Yo, what's that?  -Avocado's gear.
他今晚就可以回来了
He's getting out of the infirmary tonight.
今晚?
Tonight?
所以你有足够时间给他庆祝一下了
So you got plenty of time to bake him a cake.
我听说你在问彼得森关于贝利克的事
Hey, I heard you were asking Patterson about Bellick.
说好像你今天早上看到他了?
Said you thought you saw him this morning?
是的 我看到了
Yeah. I was.
不 应该是昨天 应该是昨天看到他的
No, it was yesterday. That's when I saw him.
-你确定?  -确定
-You sure?  -Yeah.
你知道 有时候在这儿搞不清楚时间
You know, time just sort of blends together up in here.
好吧
All right.
88号关上!
Close on 88!
我用这个干什么?
What am I supposed to do with this?
把它倒在马桶里
Pour it in the toilet.
你叫他从厨房偷洗涤液是为了洗马桶?
so we can clean the toilet?
我们今晚都得穿过精神病区到达管道那边
We got to get all of us in the psych ward tonight to access the pipes.
有一大帮穿蓝制服的狱警会在那边看守
A bunch of cons wearing their prison blues would stick out like a sore thumb.
但精神病区的囚犯都穿着...
But the inmates in the psych ward all wear...
白色
White.
-洗涤液起漂白作用  -伪装起来
-Peroxide acts as a bleach.  -Camouflage.
只有没几个小时了
Just a few more hours now.
看来该弄的都弄到了...
Looks like we got everything we need.
除了还有你哥哥
Everything except your brother.
你操心衣服的事就行了
You worry about the suits.
林肯的事由我来操心
I'll worry about Linc.
你能给我们几分钟时间吗?
Could you give us a couple of minutes?
-当然可以 总统先生  -你可能知道我此行的目的
-Of course, Mr. President.  -You probably know why I'm here.
如果我是个赌徒 我有个很好的主意该把筹码放哪儿
Lf I were a betting man, I have a pretty good idea where I'd lay my chips.
那能源议案 理查德 你怎么改变主意了?
The energy bill, Richard. Why did you change your mind?
你一直在说这太耗资金了
You've been saying for months it's so full of pork,
这东西还是放弃算了 可突然你却...
the damn thing's ready to squeal, and now all of a...
是的 那议案确实有缺陷 但总比什么都不做要好
Yes, the bill is flawed, but it's better than doing nothing.
坦白说 现在怎么轮到你站在这儿
And, frankly, I find it a little curious that you're here,
告诉我去否决这项议案 而你一直都是赞同这议案的
telling me to veto a bill you voted in favor of.
你正在摆脱困境
You're on the way out.
有些人想问题必须要有前瞻性
Some of us need to think ahead.
事实上 我也考虑了很多其它问题卡罗琳
Actually, I've been doing some thinking ahead as well, Caroline,
具体讲 关于我的"批准"问题
specifically, about my endorsement.
什么?!
What?
我在考虑是否要改变一下
I'm considering making a switch,
让参议员查理斯给我分担一些
throwing my weight behind Senator Challis.
-你不能那么做  -不能?
-You can't do that.  -Can't I?
卡罗琳 你的政治完全搞反了
Caroline, you are everything that's wrong with politics.
你投票不是要修改立法 而是要从中获利
You vote not to legislate change, but to profit.
你竞选不是要改变现状 而是要提出更多要求
You run not to make a difference, but to make demands.
你把我拉拢不是因为我能帮你提意见
You put me on your ticket not because I share your views,
而是因为我是个女性
but because I didn't share your gender.
所以不要显得很高尚 我们都知道游戏是怎么玩的
So don't take the moral high ground. We all know how this game is played.
-理查德 求你 我...  -保重 卡罗琳
-Richard, please, I...  -Good day, Caroline.
理查德! 理查德!
Richard! Richard!
你知道周年纪念的时候我给我老婆买了什么吗?
You know what I got my wife for our anniversary?
-什么?  -一条围巾
-What?  -A scarf.
这是个大周年纪念 所以我必须搞得特殊一点
Well, this is a big one for me. I had to do something special.
好 让我们把这扛到车上去
Okay, let's get this thing down to the car.
我们三个人一块儿搬
We'll do it all together on three.
准备? 1... 2... 3
Ready? One. Two. Three.
起...
不! 放下来 放下 放下
Oh, no! Oh, no! Put it down, put it down, put it down.
马上把斯科菲尔德叫过来
All right, get Scofield up here right away!
起作用了
It's working.
好 把他们晾干吧
All right, get them out and get them dry.
列队的时候我们得把这衣服穿里面
We got to get them on under our clothes before tier time,
大概还有... 45分钟时间
which is in 45 minutes.
你觉得其他人都已经准备好了吗?
You think everyone else will be ready?
我们没得选了
We don't have a choice.
门一开 我们就行动
As soon as the gate's open, we go.
我们得分秒必争
And we're gonna need every second.
打开40号门
Open on 40.
斯科菲尔德 监狱长要见你 马上
Scofield, Pope needs to see you, ASAP.
-现在?  -干什么?
-Now?  -What for?
泰姬陵 走吧
A bar mitzvah. Let's go.
已经6:18 老兄 你不能...
It's 6:15, bro. You can't...
现在!
Now!
美人儿 嘀嘀哒哒
Hey, pretty, tick-tock.
给我一分钟
Excuse me a minute.
莎拉 是什么风把你吹来了?
Sara, to what do I owe the pleasure?
我想我是来庆贺的吧
I guess to congratulations.
不敢相信我是从新闻上听到的
Can't believe I had to hear about it on the news.
那副总统的事 那只是说说而已的
Oh, the VP thing. Well, that's just talk.
是吗?
Is it?
是的 你妈妈曾怎么说?
Yeah. What was it your mother used to say?
能被邀请跳舞总是件好事
"It's always nice to be invited to the dance,
即使你没有穿对鞋子
even if you don't have the right shoes."
是的 她也常说"你是你爸爸撒谎的借口"?
Yeah. She also used to say, "Your father's a lying bastard,"
但我总把它当成是酒话
but I figured that was just the booze talking.
知道吗 看见你总能让我很开心
You know, it's always nice to see you, Sara.
你是需要什么 还是顺道看看
Is there something that you needed? Or did you just come by to...
你只需告诉我
Just tell me something.
我给你的林肯·布伦斯的材料你看过了吗?
Did you look at the information I gave you from Lincoln Burrows' attorneys?
宝贝儿 别管那事了
Sweetheart, move on.
他的律师本有机会呈上新证据
The man's attorneys had a window to present new evidence,
可他们没有 现在没这个机会了
they didn't. Now that window is closed.
我只想知道你有没有看过那些材料?
I just need to know, did you look at the information?
-别这样 莎拉  -回答我
-Come on, Sara.  -Answer me.
我敢保证  在狐狸河工作改变了你许多
I swear, working at Fox River has changed you.
你总是说你想改变现状?
You're always saying you want to make a difference?
在那个地方? 太迟了
At that place? It's too late.
你应该做一个老师 教导他们 防止他们走犯罪之路...
You should be a teacher, so that you can get to these people before they become...
你看过材料了吗?
Did you look at the information?
我没这个必要去看
I didn't need to.
我支持法庭的材料
I supported the findings of the court.
如果你对裁决有异议 那找他们去
If you have a problem with the verdict, go after them.
但在你去之前 我建议你看看这个家伙的犯罪纪录
But before you do, I suggest you look at the guy's rap sheet
你问问你自己 这世界如果多了个林肯·布伦斯
and ask yourself if the world will be a better place
会变得更美好么
with Lincoln Burrows walking the streets.
告诉我 他们是在你签署死刑令之前还是之后
Just tell me one thing. Did they promise you the vice presidency
向你保证副总统这个职位的?
before or after you signed his death warrant?
我不会与一个瘾君子或者小偷谈论道德
I will not discuss morality with an addict and a thief.
你想谈论现实 莎拉?
You want to talk reality, Sara?
我有多少次利用我的权力
How many times did I use my influence to keep you
保释过你和你的那些男朋友?
and one of your junkie boyfriends out of jail?
多少次? 3次 4次?
How many? Was it three, four times?
莎拉 这很可笑 你知道吗?
I swear, Sara, it's funny, you know?
当我为了你逾越法律的时候...
You have no trouble whatsoever with me bending the law,
你从不会觉得怎么样
especially when it's bent in your direction.
该长大了
Grow up.
你和那个孩子谈过了?
You talk to that Tweener kid?
是的 他说他把日子搞混了 我也不清楚
Yeah, he says he got his days mixed up, but I don't know.
什么?
What?
他说话的方式有点怪
Just something about the way he said it.
算了吧 伙计 贝利克只是针对他而已
Oh, come on, man, Bellick's just taking a personal.
我不想让这小子惹麻烦
I don't want to get the guy busted.
如果他不是呢?
And if he's not?
我是说 都已经6点半了 却还没人听到有他的消息
I'm just saying, it's 6:30, and no one's heard from the guy.
-我们得告诉监狱长  -好吧 我去告诉他
-We got to tell Pope.  -Okay. I'll tell him.
你叫了去机场的的士了吗?
Did you call a cab for the airport?
没 还没有
No, not yet.
为什么还没有? 快 飞机一小时后就起飞了
Why not? Come on, the flight leaves in an hour.
是啊
Yeah. Yeah.
我在想 也许去蒙大纳并不是个好主意
I'm starting to think that us going to Montana might not be a good move.
你说什么呀?
What are you talking about?
万一你说得没错 那枪都还在屋子里头
What if you are right and the smoking gun is in that house?
你以为他们会让我进去? 你以为他们会缴械自降?
You think they're just gonna let us walk in there and make a citizen's arrest?
听着 尼克 我不知道你最近怎么回事
Look, Nick, I don't know what your deal is lately,
但我无论如何都得上飞机 不管你去还是不去
but I'm getting on that plane with or without you.
我不能让你这么做
I can't let you do that.
原来你一直都和他们是一伙的?
All this time you were one of them?
谁给你下的命令 尼克? 斯蒂德曼? 凯勒曼?
Who's pulling your leash, Nick? Steadman? Kellerman?
看着我 我要你记住我这张脸
Look at me. I want you to remember my face
不管你即将怎么做
when you do whatever the hell it is you're gonna do.
看着我!
Look at me!
你是个懦夫
You're a coward.
-斯科菲尔德在外面等着 先生  -好
-Scofield's outside, sir.  -Okay.
我要你拨打和布拉德·贝利克有关的所有电话
I want you to try every number we have for Brad Bellick.
先打他家 他妈妈通常会接电话
Try his home first. His mother usually answers.
贝利克夫人? 你好
Mrs. Bellick? Hi.
请等一等 狱长有话跟您讲
One moment, please. I have Warden Pope here for you.
贝利克夫人? 没什么要紧事 没 没有
Mrs. Bellick?No cause for alarm, no, no.
我们只是... 我们今天还没见过他
We just...We haven't seen him,
我们在想 他是否在家没来
and we were wondering if he might be home under the weather.
这么说他今天到这的时候打过电话给你?
So Brad called you when he pulled in this morning?
他说他在这儿?
And he said he was here?
好 谢谢 贝利克夫人
Okay, well, thank you, Mrs. Bellick.
我们会再和你联系的 我相信他没事儿
We'll keep you posted. I'm sure he's fine.
通知麦柯 叫他检查一下车库 看有没贝利克的车
Radio Mack. Have him check the parking lot for Bellick's truck.
如果找到了 马上叫他打电话通知我
If he finds it, have him call me immediately.
457 这是总部 你那情况怎样?
457 This is base. What's your 20?
我怀孕了 费尔南多
I'm pregnant, Fernando.
我有你的孩子了
I'm gonna have your son.
但我只知道 我真的很害怕
But all I know is, is I'm really scared.
我害怕就这么孤单一个人
I'm really scared to do this alone.
约翰 从来都不会太迟
John, it's never too late.
如果你诚心想接受上帝的召唤并向他赎罪
If you'll agree to accept Christ into your heart and turn from your sin,
他会宽恕你 并解救你至永生
he will forgive you and save you in eternity.
时间合适 我就会给你菲波纳奇
I'll give you Fibonacci when the time is right.
现在正是时候
The time is right now.
不 当你我都站在高墙外面的时候 时间才会合适
No, the time is right when you and I are both standing outside those walls.
我总有一天会出去的 到时候...
I'm gonna get out of here someday, and when I do,
...别指望我不记得你家门口的样子
don't think I won't remember what your front steps look like.
我... 又要回到那边去了
I'm being shipped back off.
我得说多少次?
How many times I got to say it?
你只有一样我要的东西
You only got one thing I need.
我有个坏消息 查尔斯
I've got some bad news, Charles.
你女儿得了食道癌
Your daughter's got esophageal cancer,
趁现在还有时间 她想见见你
and she wants to see you while there's still time.
-她还能活多久?  -医院说一周
-How long does she have?  -Hospital says a week.
我在哪里看到说 真正的泰姬陵在早上会呈现出粉红色
I read somewhere where the actual Taj Mahal appears pink in the morning,
傍晚会呈现出乳白色 而当月亮升起的时候就成了金黄色
milky white in the evening and golden when the moon shines.
这种变化 他们说 相当于女子的各种不同的情绪
The changes, they say, depict the different emotions of a woman.
我可以告诉你 如果今天晚上不把这个修好
Well, I can tell you something, if we don't get this thing fixed tonight,
我可不想知道我老婆会有怎样的情绪
I don't wanna know what kind of emotion my wife is gonna have
如果我空手走进那算门
if I walk through that door empty-handed.
真奇怪 我是说 就这么倒了
It's strange. I mean, it just gave way.
我们刚把它抬起来 支撑的悬梁就断了
We lifted it up, and the support beam snapped.
-这是什么?  -支架
-What's this?  -The support.
用来支撑悬梁的
And the one that holds up that beam.
你把它拿走了?
You took it?
很抱歉...
I'm sorry.
我需要再来到这里
But I needed to get back in here.
我不明白 你为什么...
I don't understand. Why would you...
我要出去
I'm breaking out.
你得确保我哥哥和我一起走
And you're gonna make sure my brother goes with me.